and the previous video we looked at why the composition Napier was created
在之前的视频中，我们看到了为什么要创建Composition API
we're gonna review when to use the Composition API
我们要回顾一下什么时候用Compostion API
learn about the setup method and reactive reference
并且了解设置方法和响应式引用
I want to emphasize that the composition API is just additive it's a second way to write component
想强调的是，Composition只是添加剂，这是编写组件的第二种方法
All the previous component syntax that you're familiar with and Vue2.0
您熟悉的所有以前的组件语法，在Vue2.0中
you can still use its completely valid
你仍然可以使用它完全有效
The Composition API is just a more advanced
Composition API只是一个更高级的
optional syntax
可选语法
If that's the case then when should you use it
既然如此，那你什么时候该用它呢
So,here we have a component
这里我们有一个组件
and I might use the Composition API if I really care about good
我可能会使用Composition API，如果我真的在乎
TypeScripts support
TypeScript 支持
I also might use the API
我也可以用这个API
if I have a huge component
如果我有一个很大的组件
and I want to organize it by feature
我想按特点组织一下
I also might use it if I have code that needs to be reused across multiple components
如果我有代码，我也可以使用它,它需要跨多个组件重用
And lastly if I'm simply working with the team that prefers the syntax over the regular syntax
最后，如果我只是和一个团队一起工作，它比常规语法更喜欢这种语法
that might be a good enough reason
可能是个很好的理由
I'm about to show you is quite simple and you might be wondering why would I use the composition API in this case
我要向你们展示的是非常简单的，你们可能会想知道为什么我要在这个例子中使用composition API
you might be right my goal here was to make it as easy to learn as possible
你也许是对的我在这里的目标是让它尽可能容易学习
Let's take a look at a component using the regular syntax
看看使用常规语法的组件
we're printing out the capacity of an event
我们正在打印一个event的capacity
and capacity is in the data option
capacity在data这个data的option中
making it reactive
它就变成了响应式的数据了
In our browser, we see Capacity:3
在我们的浏览器中，我们看到Capacity为3
How would you write this using the Composition API
我们如何使用Composition API编写这个呢
Well,first we need to create that setup method
我们需要创建setup方法
The setup method executes before components props data methods computer properties and life cycle map
setup方法在组件属性数据方法计算机属性和生命周期映射之前执行
It also does not have access to this
它也不能访问这个
So our code inside here is gonna look different
所以里面的代码看起来会不同
setup method also has two optional arguments
setup 方法还具有两个可选参数
The first is props,
首先是props
which is reactive and can be watched
它是反应性的，可以观看
So let me show you what that might look like
让我给你看看那是什么样子
Here you can see I have a prop which is name
你可以看到我有一个props，那就是名字
and then I declare setup with the props argument
然后我用props参数声明setup
If I wanted to watch this prop for changes
我想看看这个prop的变化
I could import watch from Vue,
从视图导入监视
then I could log out to the console whenever it changes
我可以随时注销控制台
The optional second argument for setup is context
setup的可选第二个参数是context
We use context to access properties that we previously access with this
使用上下文访问我们以前访问的属性
Here are the different properties that it gives us access to
它提供给我们访问的不同属性
Now, back to our example
回到我们的例子
Here, we need to import ref from Vue
我们需要从Vue导入ref
and then declare capacity as a constant which equals ref(3)
然后声明容量为常数，等于ref(3)
The ref function creates a reactive reference
ref函数创建一个反应引用
This wraps our primitive in an object
这把我们的原语包装在一个物体里
allowing us to track changes
允许我们跟踪变化
Previously, we were using data
很明显我们用的是数据
and data was wrapping our primitives in an object for us
数据把我们的原语包装在一个对象里
Now,we'are creating a reactive reference which is an object that wraps our primitive
现在，我们正在创建一个响应式引用，它是一个包装我们的私有对象
which in this case
在这种情况下
is three
是3
As a side note with the composition API and the way Vue3.0 does reactivity
作为补充说明，使用Composition API Vue3产生响应式的方式
we can now declare reactive objects
我们现在可以声明响应式对象
that aren't associated with the components
与组件无关
which is quite powerful
相当强大
our setup method needs to return anything that needs to get access
我们的setup方法需要返回
from the template
需要从模板访问的任何内容
So,in this case,it's capacity
在这个情况下，是容量
You might initially think this is more verbose
你一开始可能认为这更冗长
but it also makes our component more maintainable,
但它使我们的组件更易于维护
am I initially think this is more for both
我最初是不是觉得这对双方都更合适
since we can control what gets exposed in our template
因为我们可以控制模板中暴露的内容
and we can more easily trace where a property is defined
我们可以更容易地定义属性
In our browser,everything is working
在我们的浏览器中，一切正常
It's worth mentioning that this Composition API syntax
值得一提的是，这个Composition API
you can use in a Vue2.0 app by using this plug in for Vue 2
通过使用此插件Vue2.0 可以在Vue2应用程序中使用
You'll want to follow the
你会想跟着
installation options on the github page
github页面上的安装选项
and then instead of importing from vue
然后不是从Vue导入
you instead import from Vue/composition API
而是从Vue/composition API导入
This is how I tested all the code I'm showing you
这就是我测试所有代码的方法